# **Thor Lindberg**

## Reykjavík, Iceland

Email thor@lindberg.is

Website lindberg.is

Courses lindberg.is/certificates

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/thorlindberg

# **Profile**

M.Sc. Design with an educational background in the intersection between medical science and information technology. With this interdisciplinary perspective I act as a bridge between clients, design teams and development teams. This is evident from my consultancy experience, where I lead project analysis with clients, wrote design specifications, and then collaborated with development teams to plan and contribute to implementation in code.

I invest my spare time in writing software, supplementing my education with courses, and traveling in the U.S. to network with others in tech.

#### **Education**

IT University of Copenhagen, 2022

# Master of Science in Digital Design

Thesis: Type-Extensible Objection Notation (TXON)

Explorative design for typedJSON objects.

## Relevant courses:

React Native mobile development with Expo.
 Advanced Design Processes. UX Design.

Copenhagen University, 2020

# **Bachelor of Science in Health Informatics**

Thesis: Tools for caretakers of stroke victims

 Qualitative analysis to determine low-cost digital solutions for caretakers of stroke victims.

# Relevant courses:

Statistics. Mathematical Modelling.
 Programming for Biosciences. IT Security.
 Medical Image Analysis. Interaction Design.

## **Skills**

Language English (fluent), Icelandic (beginner)

Figma Components, variants, flows, auto layout

Software JSX, TypeScript, Swift, SwiftUI, Git

Analysis Python, NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib

Data Excel, Visual Basic for Applications

Projects SharePoint, Azure, Office

# **Experience**

Netcompany, 08/2022 - 12/2023

#### **IT Consultant**

- Lead the analysis and initial design phase of multiple client projects and authored feature and design documents.
- Responsible for client contact, mediating meetings, status reporting, and managing the project timeline and tasks.
- Provided clients with digital transformation strategies through analysis of business processes and IT infrastructure.
- · Contributed to source code for Java-based backend.
- Contributed to code optimization and new features for a React Native and React Native for Web application.

National Special Crime Unit, 10/2021 - 07/2022

## **IT-Administrative Student**

- · Managed users of webportal and provided direct support.
- · Contributed to document processing architecture.
- · Authored documentation and website content.

IT University of Copenhagen, 08/2021 - 06/2022

## **Teaching Assistant**

- · Assisted with teaching UX Design specialization.
- Assisted with assignments for courses in UX Design, Experimental Design, Python, and Javascript with MQTT.

Domino's Pizza, 08/2021 — 01/2022

#### **Shift Leader**

- Responsible for managing the store, closing the store, registering inventory, and matching store orders with use.
- · Delegated work to bakers and delivery drivers.
- · Primary pizza baker during rush hours.

# Certificates

Mímir-simentun, 03/2024 - Now

## Introduction to Icelandic (written and spoken)

University of California, San Diego, 03/2024 - Now

## **Data Structures and Algorithms Specialization**

Courses: Test-driven algorithm design. Dynamic programming. Advanced algorithms and data structures. Pattern matching.

Meta, 03/2024 - Now

# **Front-End Developer Professional Certificate**

Courses: JavaScript. Version control. HTML and CSS. Advanced React with components, hooks, APIs, and testing. UX/UI design.

# **Published**

# Áfangastaður - Explore Iceland

iPhone application (React Native) for exploring destination in Iceland.

apps.apple.com/app/id6466740299